Chanhua (wire-wrapped florals) originated in Yingshan, Hubei.
缠花技，从湖北应山起源，
It is a form of intangible cultural heritage,
是一项非物质文化遗产，
crafted primarily with multicolored silk threads
主要是用多色丝线，
wound around a frame of cardboard and copper wire,
在纸板和铜丝扎成的骨架上，
to create decorative works depicting birds, animals, flowers and fruit.
以缠绕的方式制作出鸟兽花果的美术品。
The main steps of making are:
其主要制作步骤为：
design; cut the paper templates, trimming the shapes of leaves and petals;
设计、裁剪纸模——把叶片花瓣的形状从纸模上剪下来；
wrap the petals by winding silk thread around a copper wire frame;
缠绕花片——把它用蚕丝线缠在铜丝的骨架上；
then shape and dye each petal;
然后进行花瓣的塑形和染色；
and finally assemble everything into a finished piece.
最后将它组合成一个完整的作品。
Chanhua is known for being delicate and exquisite.
缠花具有小巧、精巧的特点，
It is a folk art with a long and storied history.
是一项拥有着悠久历史背景的民间传统技艺。
Each piece carries a sculptural, three-dimensional vitality,
每件作品都具备雕塑的立体生动感，
earning the names "three-dimensional embroidery" and "three-dimensional craft flower."
被人们称为立体绣花、立体工艺花。
My own work has evolved from the traditional flat floral form
我从最开始传统意义上的平面花，
into three-dimensional structures with a more contemporary sensibility.
发展到目前更具有现代审美的立体造型。
Lotus Under the Moon is one of my most representative pieces,
月下荷是我从艺以来比较具有代表性的作品，
blending metal wire-wrapping techniques to give the work more vitality.
融合了一些金属绕线工艺，让作品更具有生命力。
It also marked the beginning of a new stylistic phase for me.
这件作品也开启了我的一个新的风格阶段。
In this piece I designed a copper wire floral earring form,
在这件作品中，我设计了铜丝花耳造型，
and applied copper wire edging and hand-dyeing to the lotus petals.
在荷花上使用了铜丝镶边和染色工艺。
It is no longer a flat flower, it is a fully three-dimensional form.
它其实不再是一个平面的花朵，而是一个立体的造型。
Especially in the curve of each petal rising from the base,
尤其是在它花瓣弧度从底部往上走的线条中，
there is a feeling of upward growth, mimicking the way plants reach toward the sky.
它有一种向上生长的感觉，模拟自然界植物生长的造型。
Art must be rooted in nature, yet it must transcend it.
艺术要源于自然，但要高于自然。
After moving in this direction, I wanted to introduce some abstract elements.
在靠近这个方向之后，我就想要去表现一部分抽象的元素。
Spring Water was my attempt, to bring a sense of fluid movement into the tassel work.
春水就是我的一次尝试，希望在流苏里面增加一点灵动的元素。
I thought of Wu Guanzhong's paintings, those black, white, and green visions of Jiangnan.
然后就想到了吴冠中的那幅画，黑色、白色还有绿色的这种江南图境。
By adding touches of black and white into the green tassels, the whole composition comes alive.
在这个流苏的绿色里面加一点黑白的颜色，整体色彩的灵动感就会出来。
Beyond color, I also introduced geometric and abstract structural forms.
除此之外，也采用了一些几何和抽象造型的方式。
The tassels carry not just color, they also move: hanging, floating, flowing.
流苏不仅以颜色的方式来表现，它还会有一些下垂、漂浮流动的动态。
So I used tassels of different forms to express that sense of movement.
所以我使用不同造型的流苏去表达这种流动感。
Having practiced for several years now, I believe the most important quality is perseverance.
做了三五年以来，我觉得最重要的一个要素，其实是坚持。
More important, even, than talent or natural ability.
它比天分、才华这些要素甚至都要重要。
Because we all go through periods of invisibility, when no one notices the work.
因为我们总要经历无人问津、不被看到的阶段，
But rather than chasing external recognition, we must always return to our own world.
但相比去关注外界的言语，我们最终还是要回到自己的世界。
For the very act of continuing, of showing up day after day, is what moves people.
因为坚持去做一件事情的你，本身就足够打动他人。